Guide to Montana Historical Society. Research Historian records 1979-2006
Montana Historical Society
Montana Historical Society, Research Historian records
1979-2006
Montana Historical Society Archives
MHS 4
Montana Historical Society. Research Historian
7 linear feet
The Montana Historical Society’s Research Historian position was established in 1993 to “provide verification, research, writing, and editing for projects and publications by the Society and cooperating agencies.” Records consists primarily of general correspondence (1989-2006) and subject files (1979-2006). Together, the two series--between which there is considerable overlap--cover the wide range of the work of the office.
The Montana Historical Society’s Research Historian position was established in 1993 to “provide verification, research, writing, and editing for projects and publications by the Society and cooperating agencies.” The position also served as a representative of the Society at public events, conducted radio and television interviews, and served as a historical consultant.
Major projects undertaken by the office included serving as the Society’s consultant with the Montana Heritage Project, the Lewis and Clark Bicentennial Advisory Council (later renamed the Montana Lewis and Clark Bicentennial Commission), and the Virginia City/Nevada City Task Force, along with writing and editing text for the Montana history textbook for middle school students, editing interpretive script for museum exhibits, and writing biographical sketches for the “Capital Niches” and nominees for Trustees Awards.
Dave Walter was Montana Historical Society's first Research Historian. He was born in Racine, Wisconsin in 1943 and graduated from Wesleyan University in Middletown, Connecticut in 1965. He then entered the University of Montana as a graduate student, where he worked closely with historian K. Ross Toole, taught undergraduate history classes, and developed educational materials for schools. In 1979, he was hired as a Reference Librarian at the Montana Historical Society and in 1993, he became the first Research Historian at MTHS. In 1994, he received an honorary doctorate from the University of Montana.
Additionally, Walter had a regular history column in Montana, Magazine of the Northern Rockies and the Helena Independent Record. He wrote numerous articles for other publications, including Montana, the Magazine of Western History. Walter also initiated and moderated the “Jerks in Montana History: Speaking Ill of the Dead” session at the annual Montana History Conference and the "More Quarries of Last Chance Gulch" column in the Helena Independent Record, both of which became published books. He also wrote Christmastime in Montana and Campfire Tales, among other books. Walter conducted many oral history interviews, including a series of interviews on conscientious objectors during World War II, and co-authored Speaking of Montana, a guide to oral histories at the Montana Historical Society. Dave Walter died July 19, 2006.
Records consists primarily of general correspondence (1989-2006) and subject files (1979-2006). Correspondence is arranged chronologically and covers a wide range of Dave’s work, including his work on committees and his contacts with researchers.
The most substantive subject files concern the Capitol Niches (1979-2005), Legislative Minutes (2001-2003), the Lewis and Clark Bicentennial (1995-2006), the Montana Heritage Project (1994-2006), Museum exhibit planning, the Ortenberg Research Project on the Montana Legislature (1997-2000), the Golden Triangle Curriculum Cooperative’s “Thinking Through American History” project (2001-2005), the MHS Trustees’ Awards, and, and the Virginia City / Nevada City Task Force (1994-1997).
This collection is arranged into five series: 1) Biographical Materials, 2) General Correspondence, 3) Subject Files, 4) Speeches and Writings, and 5) Miscellany.
Collection is open for research
Acquisition information available upon request.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Walter, David, 1943-2006
Capitols--Montana; Education--Montana; Historical societies--Montana; History--Research-- Montana
Montana--History.
Montana
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Biographical Materials
  - Resume, biographical introductions, etc., 1997-2005 (Box-folder 1 / 1)
- General Correspondence
  - Chronological (correspondents include Edith Harper, Edith Hubble, Helen Arthur, Henry L. Armstrong, 1989-1995 (Box-folder 1 / 2)
  - Chronological (correspondents include Jane Robinson, William P. Sherman, Swarthmore College Peace Collection, Chuck Overby, Patricia Taylor, Bob Campbell, Fritz Pannekoek, Northern Plains Resource Council, Mona Vanek, Keith Edgerton, Joseph Mussulman, Marcella Sherfy Walter, Jan Battles, Harriett Meloy, Jack E. Fletcher), 1996-1998 (Box-folder 1 / 3)
  - Chronological (correspondents include J. Kevin McDonnell, Piegan Institute, Arlie J. Lane, Jack Lepley, Chuck Rankin, Brian Dippie, Ellen Ward Bertoliatti, Jack Hayne, Gerd Stolz, Patricia Grimes, John Butenhoff, William Farr, Vernon Carroll, Irene Bolander, Stephanie Tubbs), 1999 (Box-folder 1 / 4-5)
  - Chronological (correspondents include Marianne Keddington-Lang, Deidre Shaw, Chuck Rankin, John J. Walsh, Arnie Olsen, Piegan Institute, Jeff Johnson, Hannah Brown, Rebecca A. Gummer, Mark Baumler, Mark White, Jerry Girard, Sharon Randolph, Kim Alan Scott, William F. Crowley, Jack Hayne, Frank Henry, Matthew Hill, Mary Ann Dooner, Michael Umphrey, Renee Rasmusen, Dave Hagengruber), 2000 (Box-folder 1 / 6-7)
  - Chronological (correspondents include Joe Corley, John Stoner, Mae Non Robinson Ellingson, Carolyn Martin, Henry C. Klassen, Frithiof V. Johnson, Jack Hayne, David James, Vince Moravek, Gary A. Baden, Joe Trow, Montana Festival of the Book, Judy Martz, Brian W. Dippie), 2001 (Box-folder 1 / 8)
  - Chronological (correspondents include Jack Hayne, Piegan Institute, Frithiof V. Johnson, Rich Aarstad, Norma Ashby, Gil Alexander, Clark Whitehorn, Diane Smith), 2002 (Box-folder 1 / 9)
  - Chronological (correspondents include Mike Bugenstein, Phyllis Smith, Jack Hayne, Rick Newby, Derek Strahn, Michael Umphrey), 2003 (Box-folder 1 / 10)
  - Chronological (correspondents include Kirby Larson, Daniel Hall, William O'Keefe, Brian Dippie, Jim Gately, Robert A. Clark, Michael Umphrey, Tom Sargent, Lea Whitford, Sally Thompson), 2004 (Box-folder 1 / 11)
  - Chronological (correspondents include Lea Whitford, Alex Brakstad, Margaret Peck, Tom Thackeray, Arnold Olsen, Joyce Crowley, Janet Sperry, Julie Gardipee Chriske, Montana Committee for the Humanities, John L. Stoner, Michael J. Ober, Matt Schliesman, Vernon Carroll), 2005 (Box-folder 1 / 12-13)
  - Chronological (correspondents include Scott Lupo, Vernon Carroll, John L. Stoner, Mark Baumler, Jay Russell), 2006 (Box-folder 1 / 14)
- Subject Files
  - 20th Century's top ten historical events, 1999 (Box-folder 1 / 15)
  - Acquisitions Committee, 1993-2001 (Box-folder 1 / 16)
  - Acronyms, abbreviations, etc. used in Montana Historical Society reports, 2004 (Box-folder 1 / 17)
  - Alberta Project (includes cooperative exhibit planning), 1994-1998 (Box-folder 1 / 18-19)
  - American Historical Association directory entry for Montana Historical Society, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 1 / 20)
  - America's Governors' Mansions, 1996 (Box-folder 1 / 21)
  - Anaconda Company (includes charts on subsidiaries, mines and production), 1875-1944 (Box-folder 1 / 22)
  - Archaeology, 1991 (Box-folder 1 / 23)
  - Archives, undated (Box-folder 1 / 24)
  - Awards (lists of recipients), 1978-1991 (Box-folder 1 / 25)
  - Baker Massacre (Stan Gibson correspondence and article), 1994-1999 (Box-folder 1 / 26-27)
  - Beads (re trade beads, includes published articles, 1953-1975), 1995 (Box-folder 1 / 28)
  - Bibliographies on Montana history, undated (Box-folder 1 / 29-31)
  - Big Medicine (the white buffalo, also includes other white buffaloes), 1925-2000 (Box-folder 1 / 32)
  - Birdtail Butte calendar, 2002 (Box-folder 1 / 33)
  - Blackfeet Indian Reservation (includes bibliography, index to white men in 1907-1908, "Blackfeet" vs. "Blackfoot" usage, resources), 1993-1995 (Box-folder 1 / 34-35)
  - Board of Trustees (includes biographical sketches by Dave Walter), 2004-2005 (Box-folder 1 / 36)
  - Charles Bovey; Bovey collection, 1983-1994 (Box-folder 1 / 37)
  - Brands, 1957 (Box-folder 1 / 38)
  - Ian Douglas Brown (re Louis Riel), 1994-1995 (Box-folder 1 / 39)
  - Budget cuts, 2003 (Box-folder 1 / 40)
  - Buffalo (re uses of parts by Native Americans), undated (Box-folder 1 / 41)
  - Calendar essay re transportation, 2006 (Box-folder 1 / 42)
  - Canyon Ferry Visitor Center (proposed Lewis and Clark exhibit), 1996 (Box-folder 1 / 43)
  - Capitol artwork, undated (Box-folder 1 / 44)
  - Capitol drawings in map cases, undated (Box-folder 1 / 45)
  - Capitol Niches (Gallery of Outstanding Montanans; includes nominations, and research on honorees), 1979-2005 (Box-folder 1 / 46-48)
  - Capitol Niches (Gallery of Outstanding Montanans; includes biographical sketches, and research on honorees; recipients include Charlo, Raymond Gray, Ella Knowles Haskell, Norman "Jeff" Holter, Joseph Kinsey Howard, John Louis Clarke, Caroline McGill, Dorothy M. Johnson, Anthony Ravalli, D'Arcy McNickle), 1995-2005 (Box-folder 2 / 1-10)
  - Capitol plaques, undated (Box-folder 2 / 11)
  - Capitol restoration, 1997 (Box-folder 2 / 12)
  - Capitol: "Three Stars under the Capitol Dome" (includes Thomas J. Walsh, Joseph M. Dixon, Jeannette Rankin), undated (Box-folder 2 / 13)
  - Capitol tours, 1999 (Box-folder 2 / 14)
  - Career Day talk, 2002 (Box-folder 2 / 15)
  - Centennial Bell talk, 2005 (Box-folder 2 / 16)
  - Chronological lists of selected news items from various publications, 1864-1929 (Box-folder 2 / 17-23)
  - Chronologies, undated (Box-folder 2 / 24)
  - Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC), undated (Box-folder 2 / 25)
  - Civilian Public Service Camp #55, Belton (re conscientious objectors), undated (Box-folder 2 / 26)
  - Classification appeal, 1987 (Box-folder 2 / 27)
  - Grace Stone Coates, undated (Box-folder 2 / 28)
  - Colleges and universities in Montana, 1987, undated (Box-folder 2 / 29)
  - Stuart Conner, 1981, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 2 / 30)
  - Conservation group list, 1990 (Box-folder 2 / 31)
  - Cost of living in the past, undated (Box-folder 2 / 32)
  - County origins, etc., 1864-1920s (Box-folder 2 / 33)
  - Grace Dangberg Foundation (re textbook: "Montana People and their Stories"), 2005 (Box-folder 2 / 34)
  - Documents book (proposed), 2003 (Box-folder 2 / 35)
  - Dutch Henry's gun, 2000 (Box-folder 2 / 36)
  - Early expeditions of discovery, exploration, treasure hunting, etc. (list), 1852-1875 (Box-folder 2 / 37)
  - Kermit Edmonds, 2003-2006 (Box-folder 2 / 38)
  - Education Dept. (re curriculum guide and Salish-Kootenai literature kits), 1998-2003 (Box-folder 2 / 39-40)
  - Electricity deregulation, 2003 (Box-folder 2 / 41)
  - Elevation of towns in Montana, undated (Box-folder 2 / 42)
  - Employee lists, 1993-2006 (Box-folder 2 / 43)
  - Environmental organizations, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 2 / 44)
  - John C. Ewers (re nomination for American Museums Association distinguished service award), 1996-1997 (Box-folder 2 / 45)
  - Foot lockers, undated (Box-folder 2 / 46)
  - Fort Shaw girls' basketball team of 1904, 2000 (Box-folder 2 / 47)
  - Friends of the Society list, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 2 / 48)
  - "Frontier House" PBS television show, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 2 / 49)
  - Gordon Garrison "Passport to the World", 1994 (Box-folder 2 / 50)
  - Genealogical Societies in Montana (directory), 1989 (Box-folder 2 / 51)
  - Ghost towns, undated (Box-folder 2 / 52)
  - Grass roots activism in Montana outline, undated (Box-folder 2 / 53)
  - Great Northern Railway Advertising and Publicity Dept. (inventory of microfilm at Minnesota Historical Society), 1980 (Box-folder 2 / 54)
  - Arnon Gutfeld (re his research on World War I dissent, Judge Bourquin, etc.), 1991-2005 (Box-folder 2 / 55-58)
  - A. B. Guthrie conference (Center for the Rocky Mountain West), 1997 (Box-folder 2 / 59)
  - H-West (online history listserv), 2000-2002 (Box-folder 2 / 60)
  - Helena history (includes Helena Historic District, millennium chronology, millennium video), 1999-2000, undated (Box-folder 2 / 61-63)
  - Helena Society for the Preservation of Horseless Carriages, Hot Rods, and Salvaged Studebakers, 2000 (Box-folder 2 / 64)
  - Historic homes, undated (Box-folder 2 / 65)
  - History Day, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 2 / 66)
  - History magazine for 4th and 5th graders (grant proposal), 1994 (Box-folder 2 / 67)
  - "History Minutes", undated (Box-folder 2 / 68)
  - Homestead promotional brochures (list), undated (Box-folder 2 / 69)
  - Rae Horan grant (K. Ross Toole tapes), 1994 (Box-folder 2 / 70)
  - Hornaday Bison Group, Fort Benton, 1996 (Box-folder 2 / 71)
  - Humor, undated (Box-folder 2 / 72)
  - Indian Education for All, 1999-2006 (Box-folder 3 / 1)
  - Indian legislators, 1933-2005 (Box-folder 3 / 2)
  - Institute for Tourism and Recreation Research reports on Montana Historical Society, 1995 (Box-folder 3 / 3)
  - C. M. (Bill) Jacobs reminiscence as told to Miss Prather, undated (Box-folder 3 / 4)
  - Kid's packets and study guides, 1998-1992 (Box-folder 3 / 5)
  - Cindy Kittredge (re Governor's Humanities Award), 2002-2003 (Box-folder 3 / 6)
  - Ku Klux Klan records (re photocopying and microfilming), undated (Box-folder 3 / 7)
  - Land records, undated (Box-folder 3 / 8)
  - Harrison Lane (re his article on discipline in the Lewis and Clark Expedition), 2002, undated (Box-folder 3 / 9)
  - Bill Lang, 1990-2000 (Box-folder 3 / 10)
  - Last Chance Tour Train script, 1996 (Box-folder 3 / 11)
  - Legislative Minutes (includes chronological list and topical index), 2001, 2003 (Box-folder 3 / 12-13)
  - Legislature (list of special sessions), 1889-1992 (Box-folder 3 / 14)
  - Lewis and Clark air gun (article by Robert D. Beeman), undated (Box-folder 3 / 15)
  - Lewis and Clark bibliographies, undated (Box-folder 3 / 16)
  - Lewis and Clark Bicentennial Celebration Advisory Council, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 3 / 17)
  - Lewis and Clark Bicentennial Commission (correspondence, minutes, reports, etc.), 1997-2006 (Box-folder 3 / 18-25)
  - Lewis and Clark Bicentennial Commission (conference and resource directory), 1999 (Box-folder 3 / 26)
  - Lewis and Clark Bicentennial Commission Education Committee, 1998-2002 (Box-folder 3 / 27)
  - Lewis and Clark Bicentennial Commission Executive Director, 1997 (Box-folder 3 / 28)
  - Lewis and Clark Bicentennial Commission (financial), 2001-2005 (Box-folder 3 / 29)
  - Lewis and Clark Bicentennial Commission (fund-raising), 2000-2001 (Box-folder 3 / 30)
  - Lewis and Clark Bicentennial Commission (legacy document), 2002-2005 (Box-folder 3 / 31)
  - Lewis and Clark Bicentennial Commission (master plan), 2000 (Box-folder 3 / 32)
  - Lewis and Clark Bicentennial Commission (Montana Tribal Tourism Alliance), 2001-2002 (Box-folder 3 / 33)
  - Lewis and Clark Bicentennial Commission (planning), 2000 (Box-folder 3 / 34)
  - Lewis and Clark Bicentennial Commission (project proposals and grants), 2000-2004 (Box-folder 3 / 35-37)
  - Lewis and Clark Expedition (clippings of John Mullan address before Historical and Geological Society, Fort Owen), 1861 (Box-folder 3 / 38)
  - Lewis and Clark Expedition (timeline from PBS Online website), 2000 (Box-folder 3 / 39)
  - Lewis and Clark Expedition (website), 1999-2003 (Box-folder 3 / 40)
  - Lewis and Clark Expedition (miscellany), undated (Box-folder 3 / 41)
  - "List of Montanans killed or missing in action" (World War I, World War II, Korea, Vietnam), 1989 (Box-folder 3 / 42)
  - Local history course, 1996 (Box-folder 3 / 43)
  - Local history resources, undated (Box-folder 3 / 44)
  - Local history workshop, 1994 (Box-folder 3 / 44)
  - Lone Pine Rapids, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 4 / 1)
  - Long range planning (includes Mission Statement), 1993 (Box-folder 4 / 2)
  - Dennis Lutz's planned place names book, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 4 / 3)
  - Gray Mackay and Mackay Collection, 2003, undated (Box-folder 4 / 4)
  - Don MacMillan (L. P. Snyder's introduction to 2000 edition of Smoke Wars) (Box-folder 4 / 5)
  - Mike Malone (re Montana Committee for the Humanities award), 1997 (Box-folder 4 / 6)
  - Maps (includes catalog listings, sketch maps of rivers, Bob Fletcher maps of Montana, 1936, 1937), 1936-1937, undated (Box-folder 4 / 7-8)
  - Marketing Committee, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 4 / 9)
  - Thomas Francis Meagher Statue centennial celebration, 2005 (Box-folder 4 / 10)
  - Laurie Mercier, 1990-1994 (Box-folder 4 / 11)
  - Métis Days, 1997 (Box-folder 4 / 12)
  - Military organization, undated (Box-folder 4 / 13)
  - Hance Millien (re his correspondence with Jack Hayne re his booklet "Society out in Montana", 1892), 1900 (Box-folder 4 / 14)
  - Milwaukee Road right-of-way map index, undated (Box-folder 4 / 15)
  - Mining guides "Researcher's guide to Montana's abandoned mine sites" by John Westenburg, 1981 (Box-folder 4 / 16)
  - Calvin Mires (re thesis on Glacier National Park boats), 2004-2006 (Box-folder 4 / 17)
  - Missouri River ( Century Magazine article), 1887 (Box-folder 4 / 18)
  - Missouri River Headwaters State Park, 1993 (Box-folder 4 / 19)
  - Montana Club (chronology, articles, speeches, etc.), undated (Box-folder 4 / 20)
  - Montana Club (Charles M. Russell's "When the Land Belonged to God")), 1977-1988 (Box-folder 4 / 21)
  - Montana collections in the Archives of Folk Culture, Library of Congress, 2004 (Box-folder 4 / 22)
  - Montana Committee for the Humanities, 1990-2000 (Box-folder 4 / 23)
  - Montana Committee for the Humanities: Speakers Bureau, 1996-2006 (Box-folder 4 / 24)
  - Montana Constitutional Convention; Montana Constitutional Convention Society, 1972-1997 (Box-folder 4 / 25)
  - Montana Cowboy Poetry Winter camp, 2001 (Box-folder 4 / 26)
  - Montana Dept. of Fish, Wildlife and Parks, 1992 (Box-folder 4 / 27)
  - Montana Dept. of Fish, Wildlife and Parks, Ulm Pishkun exhibit planning, 1998 (Box-folder 4 / 28)
  - Montana Federation of Historical Society Workers, 1995-2006 (Box-folder 4 / 29)
  - Montana Heritage Foundation articles of incorporation, 1954 (Box-folder 4 / 30)
  - Montana Heritage Project (correspondence, meetings, proposals, etc.), 1994-2005 (Box-folder 4 / 31-37)
  - Montana Heritage Project Advisory Council, 1998 (Box-folder 4 / 38)
  - Montana Heritage Project (classroom materials re Judge Crum), 2005 (Box-folder 4 / 39)
  - Montana Heritage Project (narrative history of the project), 2000-2001 (Box-folder 4 / 40)
  - Montana Heritage Project (new position), 2000 (Box-folder 4 / 41)
  - Montana Heritage Project (primary source selections), 1998 (Box-folder 4 / 42)
  - Montana Heritage Project (project overviews), 1998 (Box-folder 4 / 43)
  - Montana Heritage Project (resource bibliographies), 1994-1997 (Box-folder 4 / 44)
  - Montana Heritage Project (talks), 1999-2005 (Box-folder 4 / 45)
  - Montana Heritage Project (teacher directories), 1998-2005 (Box-folder 4 / 46)
  - Montana Heritage Project (teacher evaluations), 1998 (Box-folder 4 / 47)
  - Montana Heritage Project (webpage materials), 1998 (Box-folder 4 / 48)
  - Montana Heritage Project (workshops, conferences, institutes), 1995-2000 (Box-folder 4 / 49-54)
  - Montana Heritage Project (workshops, conferences, institutes), 2001-2006 (Box-folder 5 / 1-5)
  - Montana Heritage Project (miscellany), 2004 (Box-folder 5 / 6)
  - Montana Historical Society and Native Americans relationship, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 5 / 7)
  - Montana Historical Society directors and librarians list, 1865-2000 (Box-folder 5 / 8)
  - Montana Historical Society Foundation: "A Thumbnail Sketch", 1984-2000 (Box-folder 5 / 9)
  - Montana Historical Society history and slide show, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 5 / 10)
  - Montana Historical Society Library (includes history), 2002-2004, undated (Box-folder 5 / 11-12)
  - Montana History Camp, 1999-2002 (Box-folder 5 / 13)
  - Montana History (brief summaries and chronologies), undated (Box-folder 5 / 14-15)
  - Montana History Conference (includes planning, program, student presentations, "Jerks"), 1994-2006 (Box-folder 5 / 16-27)
  - Montana History Education ballot initiative, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 5 / 28)
  - Montana History textbook project, 2005 (Box-folder 5 / 29)
  - Montana Indian Advisory Council, 2002 (Box-folder 5 / 30)
  - Montana Korean and Vietnam Veterans Oral History Project (grant proposal), 2002 (Box-folder 5 / 31)
  - Montana Magazine of Western History (includes lists of cover art and topics), 1951-1996 (Box-folder 5 / 32-34)
  - Montana Orphans' Home (Montana Children's Center: includes talk at reunion), 1995 (Box-folder 5 / 35)
  - Montana Veterans' and Pioneers; Building history, 2003 (Box-folder 5 / 36)
  - Montana's Conference on Race, 2002 (Box-folder 5 / 37)
  - Bob Morgan, 1996 (Box-folder 5 / 38)
  - John Mullan statue, 1996 (Box-folder 5 / 39)
  - Murdock Charitable Trust (re proposal on textbook), 2000 (Box-folder 5 / 40)
  - Museum collections policy, undated (Box-folder 5 / 41)
  - Museum exhibit planning (includes "Painting Ladies", "Spanish American War", "Off the Top: Hats and History", "A Capital Capitol", "Karl Bodmer", "Robert Scriver", "Treasure State Treasures"), 1997-2006 (Box-folder 5 / 42)
  - Museum exhibit planning ("Lure of the Parks"), 1995 (Box-folder 5 / 43)
  - Museum exhibit planning ("Montana Homeland": includes interpretive tours, student activity guides), undated (Box-folder 5 / 44-46)
  - Museum exhibit planning ("Neither Empty Nor Unknown" Montana at time of Lewis and Clark Expedition; includes Indian Advisory Panel), 2001-2006 (Box-folder 6 / 1)
  - Museum exhibit planning (Riders Under the Big Sky"), 1994-1995 (Box-folder 6 / 2)
  - Museum resources bibliography, 1994 (Box-folder 6 / 3)
  - Museum (unclaimed cultural properties: re "missing lenders" legislation), 1985 (Box-folder 6 / 4)
  - Museums Assessment Program, 1997 (Box-folder 6 / 5)
  - Museums directories, undated (Box-folder 6 / 6)
  - Joe Musselman (Governor's Humanities Award), 2005 (Box-folder 6 / 7)
  - National Archives, undated (Box-folder 6 / 8)
  - National Register of Historic Places workbook, 1994 (Box-folder 6 / 9)
  - Newspapers (includes dispersal list, Native American newspapers list, microfilming, lists of Montana newspapers, etc.), 1970s-1980s (Box-folder 6 / 10)
  - Nez Percé War (Friends of Bear Paw, Big Hole, and Canyon Creek Battlefields), undated (Box-folder 6 / 11)
  - "Nobody's Girls" (PBS program on nontraditional women of the west), 1990-1991 (Box-folder 6 / 12)
  - Northern Pacific hospital, Glendive records, circa 2005 (Box-folder 6 / 13)
  - Oral history techniques and procedures, undated (Box-folder 6 / 14)
  - Original Governors' Mansion, undated (Box-folder 6 / 15)
  - Ortenberg Research Project (Montana Legislature: includes reports by Jennifer Grimm and Eve Byron), 1997-2000 (Box-folder 6 / 16-19)
  - Joel Overholser, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 6 / 20)
  - Owl Saloon slaying, 1904 (Box-folder 6 / 21)
  - Linda Peavy and Ursula Smith, 1994-2000 (Box-folder 6 / 22)
  - Charles Peyton nomination to National Law Enforcement Officers' Memorial (re controversy over nomination and copies of contemporary news items), 1900-1909, 2001-2005 (Box-folder 6 / 23-24)
  - Political ads, 1996 (Box-folder 6 / 25)
  - Population statistics, census, etc., undated (Box-folder 6 / 26)
  - Position descriptions: Lewis and Clark Historian; Native American Coordinator, 2001 (Box-folder 6 / 27)
  - Post cards and postmarks, undated (Box-folder 6 / 28)
  - John W. Powell, 1993 (Box-folder 6 / 29)